Phil Tsarik

Highly motivated person with 5 years experience in a front end and back end development. Broad experience in working with web front end tools and frameworks as well as with pure JavaScript and HTML/CSS in modern and old browsers and different platforms. Experienced in developing of full stack web-applications using Ruby and Java.

Contacts:

• Tel: +48 534 898 187

• Email: phil.tsarik@gmail.com

• Skype: phil.tsarik

• My legal name: Pilip Tsaryk

Skill Overview

- Front end: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (incl. ES6+), TypeScript, Sass, Less
- Frameworks: Angular, React, jQuery
- Back end: Ruby, Python, Bash, Java, NodeJS, MySQL, PostgreSQL

Experience

• Front End Developer, Jul 2016–Present (4 months)

Taking part in a friend's startup as a front end developer. Responsible for a whole front end part.

- Tools & technologies used: Angular 2.x, Material design, TypeScript, JavaScript, NodeJS,
 Webpack, Karma, Jasmine, Protractor, Git, Bitbucket
- JavaScript Developer, Nov 2015–Present (12 months)

Developing a web-application for managing some specific hierarchy data which allows adding, removing, sorting, merging, exporting to Excel files, etc.

- Company: EPAM Systems, Kraków Area, Poland
- Responsibilities: UI development, writing automated tests, manual testing, taking part in meetings, architecture and UI design, making mockups, reporting
- Tools & technologies used: JavaScript, ES6, Angular 1.x, Bootstrap, Underscore, Webpack, Gulp, Bower, Karma, Jasmine, Protractor, Git, Jira

• JavaScript Developer, Apr 2014–Oct 2015 (19 months)

Developing a client application for monitoring remote servers including separate versions for desktop and mobile browsers.

- Company: SaM Solutions Gmbh, Minsk, Belarus
- Responsibilities: Planning, UI development, manual testing, taking part in meetings, UI design, making mockups, reporting
- Tools & technologies used: JavaScript, Sencha Ext JS, Sencha Touch, SASS, SCCI protocol, Sencha Architect

• Java Developer, Mar 2014–Apr 2014 (2 months)

Developing an Event Service for VMWare vCenter.

- Company: SaM Solutions Gmbh, Minsk, Belarus
- Responsibilities: Planning, DB design, developing, testing, reporting
- Tools ℰ technologies used: Java EE, Hibernate, Spring, Apache, H2 database, JUnit, Maven, Git

• Full Stack Developer, Oct 2012–Feb 2014 (17 months)

Developing a firmware with Web GUI for network-attached storages based on Debian GNU/Linux. Developed and released a complete product with periodical updates with fixes and improvements.

- Company: SaM Solutions Gmbh, Minsk, Belarus
- Responsibilities: Planning, UI and backend development, writing automated tests, manual testing, taking part in meetings, architecture and UI design, making mockups, collaborating with translators, reporting
- Tools & technologies used: Debian, Ruby, Sinatra, Rspec, Haml, HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
 jQuery, Dropbox SDK, Jasmine, Git, Jenkins, Transifex, Jira

• Java Developer, Nov 2011–Sep 2012 (11 months)

Developing client-server application which provides remote management and configuration of servers.

- Company: SaM Solutions Gmbh, Minsk, Belarus
- Responsibilities: Planning, developing, testing, reporting
- Tools & technologies used: Java SE, Java RMI, Swing, JAXB, Windows PowerShell, SVN

• Full Stack Developer, Feb 2011–Aug 2012 (19 months)

Taking part in developing of a language learning service Langaroo.

- Responsibilities: UI and backend development, writing automated tests, manual testing
- Tools & technologies used: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, ERB, SASS, Compass, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Git

Education

• Polotsk State University, 2006–2011 Diploma in Software Engineering.

Appendix

- $\bullet \ \, \rm https://www.linkedin.com/in/tsarik$
- https://github.com/phts
- $\bullet \ \, https://stackoverflow.com/users/2462524/phts$